Ogundotun Balikiz

Frontend Developer

PROFILE

I am a Frontend developer with expertise in developing responsive websites and proficiently implementing Figma designs. I have a keen interest in acquiring knowledge about the latest technologies, transforming concepts into actuality, and working alongside committed teams to create effective and resilient applications.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend DeveloperHero Technologies

09/2022 – 01/2023
Abuja, Nigeria

- Develop new user-facing features
- Collaboration with team members to ensure technical feasibility of designs
- Build reusable codes
- Working with APIs to ensure interactivity.

Frontend Developer

O2/2023 – O5/2023

Nigeria Police Force Central motor Registry

Abuja, Nigeria

- Meeting with development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications.
- Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.
- Identifying web based user interactions.
- Developing and implementing highly responsive user interface components.
- Troubleshooting and debugging application codes.
- Monitoring and improving frontend performances.
- Documenting application changes and developing updates.

Frontend Developer (Contract)

Paritie Dynamic Enterprise Limited 🤌

05/2023 – 10/2023 Nigeria

- Creating reusable and efficient React components to enhance code maintainability and scalability.
- Building responsive web applications that work seamlessly across different devices and screen sizes.
- version control with Git and efficient collaboration within the development team

LANGUAGES

Html	••••	Css	• • • • •
Javascript	• • • • •	Reactjs	• • • • •
Bootstrap	••••	Tailwindcss	• • • • •

PROJECTS

E-commerce website \mathscr{D}

Central Motor registry 02/2023 – 05/2023

https://cmris.npf.gov.ng/

Striit App *⊗* 2023

Striit is more than just an app to check for available parking spots and bylaw updates. It's a community of drivers and app users helping one another avoid parking tickets, keeping cars safe, and making parking better—together.

Maturation farm 2024

https://www.maturationfarm.com/

Maturation Farm was developed using React.js to showcase the richness of the business and highlight their offerings in sustainable agriculture. They specialize in acquiring and managing premium agricultural assets for both private and institutional investors.

Pricefic *⊗* 2023 – 2024

A product of https://pheeque.com/

SKILLS

Practical knowledge of
Frontend Technologies

Html5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, REACTJS, TAILWIND AND BOOTSTRAP CSS

Version control

Proficient understanding of Git and Github.

Collaboration

Strong team spirit

Adaptability

Adaptability to environmental condition and technological advancement

REST APIs

Experience with REST APIs and third-party libraries

Organizational skill

Planning and ability to work with time

Learning Ability

Quick and sound learning ability

EDUCATION

BAgric/Animal Science

Osun State University

2011 – 2016 Osogbo, Nigeria

CURRENTLY LEARNING

PHP — Competent

Mysql — Competent

Laravel — Competent